# Junheng Hao

CONTACT INFORMATION

UCLA Computer Science, Samueli School Of Engineering University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA)

*E-mail:* jhao@cs.ucla.edu *Mobile:* +1 (424)355-5950

Homepage LinkedIn Google Scholar Semantic Scholar

RESEARCH INTERESTS Knowledge is power; knowledge graphs (KGs) are power to next-generation AI Analytics. My research interests lie at the intersection of graph learning, data mining, natural language processing and machine learning with a focus on knowledge bases and graphs, especially learning symbolic and semantic structures inside KGs and its empowered interdisciplinary applications. My research goal is to develop: TBA

**EDUCATION** 

### University of California Los Angeles (UCLA), CA, USA

June 2022 (Expected)

Ph.D. in Computer Science

**Thesis:** Incorporating ontological information in knowledge graph learning and applications **Advisors:** Yizhou Sun, Wei Wang

**Area of Study:** Knowledge graph, graph mining, natural language processing, machine learning, bioinformatics, recommender systems.

### Tsinghua University, Beijing, China

May 2017

B. Eng. in School of Information Science and Technology

B. Sc (Econ, Minor) in School of Economics and Management

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (INDUSTRY)

# Research Intern at Microsoft Research (MSR), Redmond, WA

June 2021 - Sept 2021

- Mentors: Chieh-Han Wu, Zhihong (Iris) Shen, Ye-Yi Wang, Jennifer Neville
- **Project:** KG-enhanced document representation learning
  - Overview: Enhancing document pretrained representations with infused document knowledge graph (DocKG), including Microsoft Academic Graph (Content + Graph).
  - **Deliverables:** One research technical preprint [12] under review.

#### PhD Research Intern at IBM Research AI, San Jose, CA

June 2020 - Sept 2020

- Mentor: Mentors: Chuan Lei, Berthold Reinwald, Fatma Ozcan
- **Project:** Ontology Matching by Utilizing Graph Neural Networks
  - Overview: Empowering hybrid graph neural networks (GNNs) for ontology matching between relational databases and standard healthcare ontologies.
  - **Deliverables:** One paper [1] published at KDD 2021 with corresponding invention filed and partially shipped in *IBM Micromedex solutions (Watson Health)*.

# Applied Scientist Intern/Student Researcher at Amazon, Seattle, WA June 2019 - Dec 2019

- Mentors: Tong Zhao, Luna Xin Dong, Christos Faloutsos
- Project: Diversified Complementary Recommendation on Product Graph
  - Overview: Enabling diversified complementary recommendation from web-scale product graphs and hierarchical product ontology.
  - **Deliverables:** One paper [3] published at CIKM 2020 and deployed in *Amazon-wide* product complementary recommendation engine.

#### Research Intern at NEC Lab America, Princeton, NJ

June 2018 - Sept 2018

- Mentors: Lu-An Tang, Zhichun Li, Haifeng Chen
- Project: Diversified Complementary Recommendation on Product Graph
  - Overview: Graph-based Multi-source graph knowledge transfer and network fusion on enterprise engines for malicious process detection.
  - Deliverables: One research technical preprint [11] under review.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (ACADEMIA) **Graduate Student Researcher** at University of California, Los Angeles Sept 2017 - Present

- Project 1: MurderBook: Homicide Knowledge Graph
  - Collaborators: P. Jeffrey Brantingham (UCLA Department of Anthropology), Wei Wang
  - **Overview:** Constructing case knowledge graphs for Los Angeles homicide investigation to improve search, analysis and solvability.
- Project 2: Knowledge Graph Inference on Texera Platform
  - Collaborators: Chen Li (UC Irvine), Wei Wang
  - Overview: Implemented knowledge graph completion module, such as COVID-19 drug repurposing pipeline, on Texera (one online platform for code-free collaborative modularized ML).
- Comprehensive KG Representation Learning Framework
  - Advisors: Wei Wang, Yizhou Sun (Scalable Analytics Institute)
  - Overview: Incorporating ontologies and semantics in encyclopedia knowledge graphs and wide-ranging biological knowledge bases (gene ontologies, proteins, pathways and reactions, etc).

# PUBLICATION SUMMARY

As of December 2021: I have accomplished 10+ Papers published papers and submissions, among which I first-authored papers published on top-tier venues (KDD, CIKM, BCB) from interdisciplinary domains across machine learning, data mining and bioinformatics. These papers have received 150+ Citations. More up-to-date publication record can be found in *Google Scholar* and/or *Semantic Scholar*. Several research works and internship projects (such as P-Companion[3]) have been successfully deployed in market-scale product.

## PUBLICATIONS, SUBMISSIONS & PREPRINTS

- [1] MEDTO: Medical Data to Ontology Matching using Hybrid Graph Neural Networks **Junheng Hao**, Chuan Lei, Abdul Quamar, Vasilis Efthymiou, Fatma Ozcan, Yizhou Sun, Wei Wang.
  - Proceedings of 27th ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery & Data Mining (KDD, Applied Data Science Track). Auguest 2021.
- [2] JEDI: Circular RNA Prediction based on Junction Encoders and Deep Interaction among Splice Sites
  - Jyun-Yu Jiang, Chelsea J.-T. Ju, **Junheng Hao**, Muhao Chen, Wei Wang. Proceedings of the 29th annual international conference on Intelligent Systems for Molecular Biology and the 20th annual European Conference on Computational Biology (ISMB-ECCB). September 2021.
- [3] *P-Companion: Framework for Diversified Complementary Product Recommendation* **Junheng Hao**, Tong Zhao, Jin Li, Luna Xin Dong, Christos Faloutsos, Yizhou Sun, Wei Wang.
  - Proceedings of the 29th ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM), Applied Research Track. October 2020.
- [4] Bio-JOIE: Joint Representation Learning of Biological Knowledge Bases

  Junheng Hao, Chelsea J.-T. Ju, Muhao Chen, Yizhou Sun, Carlo Zaniolo, Wei Wang.

  Proceedings of The 11th ACM Conference on Bioinformatics, Computational Biology, and
  Health Informatics (ACM BCB 2020), September 2020. Best Student Paper Award.
- [5] Universal Representation Learning of Knowledge Bases by Jointly Embedding Instances and Ontological Concepts
  - **Junheng Hao**, Muhao Chen, Wenchao Yu, Yizhou Sun, Wei Wang. Proceedings of 25th ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery & Data Mining (KDD, Research Track). August 2019.
- [6] Accident Impact Analysis in Traffic Safety and Mobility Using Group Network Features Chen-Shuo Sun, Xin Pei, Junheng Hao, Zuo Zhang.

Transportation Research Part B: Methodological (TRB), 2018.

[7] Normal/Abnormal Heart Sound Recordings Classification Using Convolutional Neural Network

Tanachat Nilanon, Jiayu Yao, Junheng Hao, Yan Liu.

Proceedings of the 43rd Computing in Cardiology Conference (CinC). December 2016.

- [8] A Data Driven Approach for Evaluation of Urban Accident Impacts Chen-Shuo Sun, **Junheng Hao**, Xin Pei, Zuo Zhang.
  - Proceedings of IEEE Conference on Intelligent Transportation Systems (ITSC), December 2016.
- [9] Metadata-Induced Contrastive Learning for Zero-Shot Extreme Multi-Label Text Classification

Yu Zhang, Zhihong Shen, Chieh-Han Wu, Boya Xie, **Junheng Hao**, Ye-Yi Wang, Kuansan Wang and Jiawei Han.

Prerpint, under review.

[10] A Mobility-Aware Longer-Term Deep Learning Model for COVID-19 PandemicPrediction with Policy Impact Analysis

Danfeng Guo, Zijie Huang, **Junheng Hao**, Yizhou Sun, Wei Wang, Demetri Terzopoulos. Prerpint, under review.

- [11] MSGT-GNN: Multi-source Graph Knowledge Transfer
  - **Junheng Hao**, Lu-An Tang, Yizhou Sun, Zhengzhang Chen, Haifeng Chen, Junghwan Rhee, Zhichun Li and Wei Wang.

Prerpint, under review.

- [12] KG-Doc: Hybrid Knowledge Graph Infused Document Representation Learning **Junheng Hao**, Chieh-Han Wu, Iris Zhihong Shen, Boya Xie, Jennifer Neville, Ye-Yi Wang, Yizhou Sun, Wei Wang. Preprint, under review.
- [13] MurderBookKG: Homicide Analysis from Automatic Case Knowledge Graph Construction **Junheng Hao**, Jingyue Shen, P. Jeffrey Brantingham, Wei Wang. Preprint, under review.
- [14] Neighbor Aggregative Network Embedding Yunsheng Bai, Ruchi Jain, **Junheng Hao**, Yang Qiao, Zixia Weng, Yizhou Sun, Wei Wang. Preprint.
- [15] Latent Translational Dialogue State Tracking Muhao Chen\*, Junheng Hao\*, Jyun-Yu Jiang, Zijun Xue, Yizhou Sun, Carlo Zaniolo, Wei Wang. Preprint.

### PATENT APPLICATIONS

[16] OntoGNN: Hybrid Graph Neural Networks for Ontology Matching. Chuan Lei, Junheng Hao, Vasilis Efthymiou, Fatma Ozcan, Abdul Quamar. U.S. Patent Application. (Sept. 2021)

# ACADEMIC SERVICES

#### **Conference Program Committee / Reviewer**

<ul> <li>Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)</li> </ul>	2021
• SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD)	2019-2021
• International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML)	2020-2022
AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI)	2021,2022
• The WebConf / International World Wide Web Conference (WWW)	2022
• International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)	2020-2022
• International Joint Conferences on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI)	2020-2022
• IEEE International Conference on Data Engineering (ICDE)	2020
• Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)	2019

• SIAM International Conference on Data Mining (SDM)	2019-2022
Program Committee Board • International Joint Conferences on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI)	2022-2024
<ul> <li>Journal Reviewer</li> <li>IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence</li> <li>IEEE Transactions on Big Data (TBD)</li> <li>ACM Transactions on Intelligent Systems and Technology (TIST)</li> <li>ACM Transactions on Knowledge Discovery from Data (TKDD)</li> </ul>	Γ)
<ul> <li>Conference Volunteer</li> <li>International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)</li> <li>SIKKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</li> <li>Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processi</li> <li>Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)</li> </ul>	ing (EMNLP) 2020, 2021
• Dec 2021: Coupang, Ranking, Discovery and Personalization. Invited tech talk: <i>Knowledge Graphs Meets Product Recommend Solution</i> .	lation: One Deep Learning
<ul> <li>Oct 2021: UCLA CS Data Science Seminar Graphs, Transformers, and When They Meet Biology (AlphaFold</li> </ul>	72). [Video]
<ul> <li>Aug 2021: Microsoft Search, Assistant and Intelligence (MSAI) Graph learning session: Knowledge Graph with Ontology Learning</li> </ul>	
• July 2019: Amazon, Product Graph. Invited talk: Representation Learning on Knowledge Graphs: En Graph Neural Networks (with Yizhou Sun).	mbedding, Logic Rules and
<ul> <li>Best Student Paper Award (ACM BCB)</li> <li>SIGIR Student Travel Grant (CIKM)</li> <li>Student Travel Award (KDD)</li> <li>UCLA Graduate Division Fellowship</li> </ul>	2020 2020 2019, 2020 2018-2019
• CS M146: Introduction to Machine Learning (Instructor: Sriram Sankararaman).  Teaching Associate / Head TA, Winter 2021 Evaluation Score: <b>8.2</b> /9.0	
• CS145: Introduction to Data Mining (Instructor: Yizhou Sun) Teaching Associate / Head TA, Fall 2020	Evaluation Score: <b>8.0</b> /9.0
<ul> <li>CS32: Introduction to Computer Science II, Data Structures (Inst Carey Nachenberg)</li> <li>Teaching Assistant, Spring 2019 &amp; Winter 2019</li> </ul>	tructor: David Smallberg &
• CS145:Introduction to Data Mining (Instructor: Yizhou Sun) Teaching Assistant, Fall 2018	
<ul> <li>UCLA Volunteer Income Tax Assistance (VITA) Organization: Income Tax Assistance (VITA) Organization: UCLA Bruin Mental Health Advisory Committee: Representative</li> <li>UCLA GUM: Graduate-Undergraduate Mentorship Program: Seinar PhD Mentor</li> </ul>	ve and advocate volunteer

# EXTRACURRICULA

ACTIVITIES

INVITED TALKS

HONORS AND AWARDS

TEACHING

• UCLA CS PhD Mentorship Program: Seinor PhD Mentor

SKILLS

- **Programming:** Python (PyTorch, TensorFlow), C/C++, LATEX, MATLAB, SQL **Language:** Mandarin (Native), English (Proficient), Spanish (Basic)